Finding Aid for Royal Arch Masons, Washtenaw Chapter No. 6 records, 1849-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Royal Arch Masons, Washtenaw Chapter No. 6 records 1849-1972
Royal Arch Masons. Washtenaw Chapter No. 6 (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
3 linear feet and 1 oversize volume
2010005 Bd 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from the chapter (donor no. 10270 ) in 2009.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
On October 15, 1849 a meeting was held in Ann Arbor, Michigan for the purpose of establishing a Royal Arch Masons chapter. At the annual convocation of the Grand Chapter of Michigan on January 3, 1850, a charter was granted for this chapter which would be called Washtenaw No. 6. At this same meeting, the chapter was granted seats in the convocation and given the right to vote in the proceedings of the Grand Chapter.
The records include minutes of meetings, the annual reports to the Grand Chapter Royal Arch Mason of Michigan, pocket registers of membership, and a financial ledger.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Freemasonry--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Royal Arch Masons. Washtenaw Chapter No. 6 (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
- Minute Books
  - 1849-1858 (Box 1)
  - 1858-1969 (Box 1)
  - 1969-1882 (Box 1)
  - 1882-1890 (Box 1)
  - 1890-1904 (Box 1)
  - 1905-1913 (Box 1)
  - 1913-1926 (Box 2)
  - 1926-1943 (Box 2)
  - 1948-1958 (Box 2)
  - 1959-1972, 9 folders (Box 3)
    (the minutes have been placed into folders)
- Other Records
  - Ledger, ca. 1856-1875 (Box 3)
  - Pocket notebooks containing register of members, register of conferring degrees, etc., 1 expandable folder (Box 3)
  - Annual Return to the Grand Chapter Royal Arch Mason of Michigan, 1 expandable folder (Box 3)
    (reports on membership, etc.)
  - Register of members, 1860-1906 (Volume 1)
    (include dates of advancement, passing, reception, exaltation, and membership)